Nanbei, stop!
南北你给我站住
Stop there!
别跑
Nanbei!
南北
Bei...
北
You!
你跑
No more running?
你再跑
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
Play something for us?
给个点呗
Last semester,
上学期
we participated in
我们一共接到校外
fifteen competitions outside the school.
十五场比赛
We won four of them
赢了四场
and lost eleven.
输了十一场
There's one thing I'm certain of.
唯一值得可以肯定的是
I've become the best debater
凭借我的个人实力
in these four competitions
拿下了这四场的
because of my talents and skills.
最佳辩手
Why don't we talk about
你怎么不说说
the other eleven competitions
另外十一场
which we lost?
是怎么输的呢你
It's just bad luck.
缺点运气吧
Bad luck?
缺点运气吗
Do you really think that it's bad luck?
是缺点运气吗
How dare you say that.
好意思说呢
If it wasn't because of you
要不是你口嗨
making fun of their lecturer's baldness,
天天吐槽人家教授秃头
we shouldn't have lost that many times.
咱们能输那么多
Did I?
有吗
It's just like how wearing a wig or not
就像戴不戴假发
is a personal preference.
只是个人选择罢了
Isn't that right, sir?
是不是老师
We can't say that certain changes are good
不能因为某些事
just because something happened
少了某些麻烦
that resulted in fewer annoyances.
就说这种变化是好的
For example, our judge,
就像咱们评委老师
he doesn't need to wash his hair anymore.
他也少了洗头的麻烦
You can ask him if it's good or not.
你问他是好 还是不好
If I do it again,
那下次如果我那样
please pinch my thigh.
你就拧我大腿
In last week's competition,
上个礼拜那场我
I've already pinched the heck out of it.
都拧成什么样了
Did it stop you?
我拦得住你吗我
I'm telling you that you must practice.
我跟你讲你好好训练
Stop fooling around with those petty tricks.
别靠那些旁门左道
Petty tricks?
旁门左道
Are you saying that I'm using petty tricks?
这叫旁门左道吗
For us,
对于咱们来说
what do you think we need most right now?
现在最需要的是什么
We need more new blood.
是新鲜血液
We need publicity.
是知名度
I've heard
我听说了
our school is currently disbanding
现在学校正在取缔
clubs which don't have enough members.
人数不够的社团
Are you saying
你的意思我们
that our club might get disbanded?
有可能被废社
Nonsense.
妖言惑众
According to what you said earlier
根据你去年说的
about our club's performance in last year,
咱们成绩的情况
we're in real danger.
岌岌可危
No way will we get disbanded.
绝对不可能
Where did you get
您哪儿来的
your confidence from?
那么些自信啊
There are three reasons why I am sure.
我确信的理由有三个
First
第一
Little Xiaoyu, our lucky mascot
从大一开始
who has accompanied me
就陪伴在我身边的
since my first year in university.
吉祥物 小小鱼
As long as we have it in our debate club,
有它陪伴我们辩论社
nothing bad
那是一点不好的事情
will ever happen to us.
都不会发生
Ah, right.
对了
I wasn't at home during the weekend,
我周末不在家
so I've entrusted it to you.
放在你那儿了
Is it still alright?
它现在还好吧
Is this alright?
合适吗
I've only ever seen people walk their dogs.
我就见过遛狗
This is the first time I see someone walk a tortoise.
可没见过遛乌龟的啊
No problem.
没事
Look how happy it is.
你看它多开心啊
Hurry up! We are waiting for you two!
快点 就差你们俩了
Coming!
来了
It's currently resting
它现在坐拥顶配豪宅
in a luxurious mansion,
南北通风
well-ventilated,
正在一个
in the shade
太阳四十五度角
where sunlight is coming
的阴凉处
in a 45-degree angle.
休息呢
That's good.
挺好的
Second
第二
What do you think our debate team is?
咱们辩论队是什么
It's a club founded by our old coach
那是老教练一手创办的
with decades of history.
风雨数十载
It's like his flesh and bone.
那是他的心头肉啊
I believe
我相信
that as long as our old coach is still breathing,
只要有老教练一口气在
he will never allow
就绝对不会允许
anything bad happen
任何对辩论队
to our debate team.
不利的事情发生
Nurse! He's not breathing!
他没有呼吸了 护士
Sa.
小撒
I'm here.
在 在
Coach, I'm here.
老教练 我在这儿呢
The debate team...
辩论队
What's with the debate team?
辩论队怎么了
Go to Tao Hao.
找陶好
Third,
第三
which is the most important point.
也是最最最重要的
We have Tao Hao in our team.
咱们队有陶好姐
Good morning, sir.
老师好
Tao Hao.
陶好
Send this to the administration office for me.
帮我送到教务处
Alright.
诶 好的
Tao Hao.
陶好
We're going to the meeting.
我们先去开会了
Remember to send us the documents.
资料记得一会儿送来
Alright.
好的
Mr. Li.
李主任
Hey.
哎哎
Hao, you're here.
小好 你在啊
Mr. Li.
李主任
Can you please take a look at this?
正好您看一下
This is our club fund applications
这是我们这学期
for this semester.
社团费用的申请
Tao Hao.
小好
This office
这办公室
cannot operate without you.
离了你还真不行
The student council is very smart
学生会选了你呀
for choosing you.
我真是太明智了
These are my responsibilities.
这都是我应该做的
With these guarantees, there is no way we'll get disbanded.
三重保障 万无一失
Hey!
这两位同学
Where do you think you're going?
你们在做什么呢
Didn't class end?
不是下课了吗
Yeah.
就是
I heard the bell rang just now.
刚才我们听见铃响了
We're in the middle of class!
课才上了一半
Go back to your seats!
快给我坐回座位
We heard wrong. I'm sorry.
幻听 对不起
I'm sorry, sir. I'm sorry.
对不起 老师 对不起
Meet me at the small garden after class.
下课小花园集合
Be prepared.
全力备战
Why do we need to prepare?
备什么战
It's about tomorrow.
明天那件事
Oh.
哦
Dango has fallen in love with a handsome guy
团子看上一帅哥
and wants to confess, right?
要表白了是吧
Tell me the whole story.
过程 过程给我讲讲
What is this?
这是什么
It's the whole story.
过程
She can hear us from there?
这都能听见
Alas.
哎
Why are you sighing?
叹什么气呀
Let her chase after her love interest freely.
人家喜欢就让人追呗
You may not know this,
你是不知道
but when Dango fell in love
以前的时候
with a handsome guy in the past.
团子也相中过一个男神
She fell in love at first sight and projected too far into the future.
一见钟情 一眼万年
She even prepared
连俩人孙女家
their granddaughter's
的猫的名字
cat's name.
都想好了
One week later, she confessed
一周之后高调告白
in front of the whole school.
全校皆知
Did she succeed?
成了吗
Of course...
当然
Not.
没有
Don't worry.
放心吧
That's the past.
以前是以前
She has me now.
现在有我呢
I'll make sure she will get him
保证给她整得轰轰烈烈
in one go.
的一举拿下
The reason why I'm here
我这次来呢
is to talk to you about
就是想跟你说说
the debate team.
辩论队的事情
Don't worry, Mr. Li.
主任 您放心
In the next competition,
下场比赛
and the provincial competition after that,
和之后杀入省赛
I've already made thorough preparations.
我都有一个周全的计划
Well...
这个 这个 这个
About the debate team.
辩论队啊
After we have discussed in the school committee,
我们经过校团委
we've unanimously decided
共同决定
that the team of Western University of Science and Technology
合并后的校队
should represent us after the merger.
就由西科大校队担任
I don't think
下周比赛
you need to go to the competition next week.
我觉得你们就不用去了
There's no meaning of it.
去了也没什么意义
But you can't just
那我 我们队
disband our team like that, can you?
总不能解散吧
Our team is disbanded?
我们队解散了
You can think of it that way.
也可以这么认为
Look at the team of Western University of Science and Technology,
你看人西科大
they won the second prize in the national competition last year.
去年这个比赛全国亚军
We all saw that.
这个成绩有目共睹啊
This is good for the school.
都是为了学校好
Go back
你回去给他们
and have a nice talk with them.
好好做做工作啊
Yes.
嗯
I understand.
我知道了 知道了
Did you get the balloons?
气球买了吗
Miss,
大姐
they don't sell balloons in the supermarket.
超市哪里有卖气球的
Which supermarket sells balloons?
谁家超市卖气球啊
You're yelling at me again.
你又凶我
Alright, I'm sorry.
好 知道了 对不起
I'll buy some for you right away, alright?
我等下就去买 好吗
Yes.
嗯
Bye.
拜拜
So, why didn't you tell her?
那你还不赶紧告诉她
I just saw him
我就只是看见人家
in the Fenglinwan Hotel.
在枫林湾宾馆里面
I didn't see any
我又没有看到
crucial evidences.
关键性的证据
Consider the name of this hotel.
你听听这个名字
How can this be proper?
这宾馆这名它能正经吗
Besides,
再说了
what else can a single man and woman
孤男寡女
do in a hotel?
去宾馆能干嘛呀
Practicing their scripts?
对剧本啊
What if they're really practicing their scripts?
万一人家就是对剧本呢
Then, I should say
那我还说他们
they went to the hotel to play poker.
去宾馆打扑克呢
Even if it's true,
就算是板上钉钉的事
Dango might not believe me.
团子万一不信我
What should I do?
怎么办呀
Why won't she believe you?
她怎么可能不信你
What if I tell you that the shoes that
我要说你脚上的这个
cost more than one thousand yuan
花一千多块钱
are fake,
买的是个假货
will you believe me?
你信吗
Impossible!
不可能
That's not true.
怎么可能呢
You see?
你看吧
People will only believe
人就只会相信
what they choose to believe.
自己愿意相信的东西
I think you girls
我就发现你们
think too much.
女孩事太多
You only need
你就跟她
to tell her directly, right?
直接说不完了吗
Okay.
来
Show me.
你给我说说
Show me how you will do it.
换你你怎么说
Alas.
哎
You tell her,
你就跟她说
Dango.
团子呀
Yes.
嗯
Your Prince Charming.
你男神
With another person...
跟人家
That...
那个了
What?
哪个了
Um...
就
I think your concerns
我觉得你的担心
are valid.
很有必要
Are you going to tie, stick
这两个绑起来 贴起来
or hang these two together?
还是挂起来呀
Just hang them over there.
就挂在那边
But I don't think green is good.
但是我觉得绿色不好看
I like pink.
我喜欢粉色
Green is good.
绿的好
Everyone is here.
大家都在啊
That's good.
正好
I need to tell you something.
我要跟大家说一件事
It's about our old coach.
是关于老教练的
Basically,
事情
that's how things are.
就是这样
Is the coach okay?
那老教练没事吧
He's alright.
还好
A month of bed rest, and he should be fine.
卧床一个月就可以了
But in the future,
不过以后啊
he has to quit smoking and drinking.
戒烟戒酒是肯定了
The coach said
老教练交代了
not to go see him,
让你们不要去看他
prepare for the competition instead.
好好准备比赛
That's good. I was so worried.
那就好 吓死我了
Not bad, Sa.
不错啊 小撒
You've suddenly
摇身一变
transformed into our coach.
变我们教练了
There's another thing.
还有一个事情
I'll let the captain tell you about it.
让队长来给你们宣布吧
What is it, Hao?
什么呀 小好姐
Tell us.
就是 快说
You're making me nervous.
急死我了
The topic for the debate on Friday is out.
周五比赛的辩题出来了
Is it ever necessary to conceal something out of kindness?
善意的隐瞒有没有必要
We're opposing, it's not necessary.
我们是反方 不必要
I think we have the advantage.
我觉得有优势
This is the first competition
这是我们这个学期
of this
开学以来
semester.
第一个比赛
I hope you'll all prepare for it.
希望大家好好准备
Don't worry, Hao.
放心吧 小好姐
We have the best debater
咱们队里有一个
in our team.
最佳辩手
Then, Sa.
那 小撒
We'll go organize things
那我们去安排一下
for the day of the competition...
比赛那天的情况
Right.
对
There's still a lot of stuff
还有一堆事情
we haven't sorted out.
没有处理呢
You guys prepare for the competition.
你们好好准备比赛
What are you doing
这么多气球
with this many balloons?
你们弄来做什么
Oh!
噢
They're for
那个是为了
an early victory celebration!
提前庆祝比赛胜利
Yeah!
对对对
We're gonna win!
比赛胜利 胜利
Get ready for the competition.
好好准备比赛
Quick.
快快快
Hurry.
赶紧的
Don't delay my confession!
别耽误我表白
You just told them
刚才你让他们
to keep preparing for the debate.
继续准备比赛
Is there a way
是有办法
we can get the competition back?
把比赛抢回来吗
No.
没有
Seeing how excited they were for the debate,
看他们积极备赛的样子
I just couldn't bear to
我实在是不忍心
tell them.
告诉他们
And I still want to try again.
而且我还想再试试
They may seem to be
你别看他们
messing around every day,
平时吊儿郎当的
they all love debating.
其实都特别喜欢打辩论
So,
所以
I'm going to talk to
我明天准备找
Mr. Li tomorrow and try again.
李主任再争取一下
Are you with me?
跟我一起吗
Of course.
当然
Now I'm still
我现在可还是
your coach.
你们的教练
Of course, I'll fight with you
当然跟你们战斗到
until the end.
最后一刻呀
Last night,
我昨天晚上
I made a long list of reasons
列了一堆理由
why she'd want to know
她想知道的
and why she wouldn't.
不想知道的
I got the same number for both.
俩理由一样多
How do you know that
你怎么知道人家
Dango wouldn't want to know?
团子不想知道
Just put yourself in her shoes!
你就换位思考
For example, you've been looking at a restaurant for a long time,
你看上一家馆子很久了
and you finally got to eat there.
好不容易要去吃了
Then I tell you,
我告诉你
this restaurant is absolutely disgusting and
这家馆子脏得要死
dirty.
特别脏
I'd be unhappy.
不乐意
But at least it's the truth.
但这个至少是真话
You can't fix anything by hiding it.
你隐瞒什么都解决不了
Then what can I fix now?
那我现在能解决什么
I can't fix that guy.
我又解决不了那男的
I can't fix anything.
我什么都解决不了
Isn't Dango
我不是只能
the only one I can fix?
解决团子了吗
Yeah.
是是
What would you like?
吃点什么
Three pork burgers.
要三个肉夹馍
Three pork burgers, alright.
三个肉夹馍 好嘞
That's 21 in total.
一共二十一
Just give me 20.
您给二十得了
He didn't see.
他没看见
What are you doing?
不 你干嘛呢
I...
我
Nothing...
没 没
Where did you put the money?
放钱哪
I...
我
I told you.
我说啥了
People don't believe things
人是不会相信
they don't see with their own eyes.
自己没看到的东西
These people...
什么人都有
What the...
一天天的
Give him the money.
给钱吧
Look how little I have left.
就剩这么点了
Dango.
团子
That day I was
我 我那天去
out shopping...
买东西的时候吧
It's Hao.
小好姐
Here.
这这这 这边
What are you doing?
干嘛
There are balloons in the back.
后面有气球
Hao.
小好姐
How are preparations for the debate going?
比赛准备得怎么样了
Have you been slacking off?
有没有偷懒
Relax.
你放心吧
We wouldn't slack off.
我们不会偷懒的
This competition is very important.
这场比赛很重要
You need to really go for it!
你们得加把油啊
I'm still be the first speaker this time.
这次我还是负责一论
I'll send over my draft
一会儿我把立论稿的
of points in a second.
散点发过去
You guys sort out the structure.
你们好好梳理一下框架
We'll discuss it later.
回头我们再一起讨论
OK.
好
I don't know
不知道
whether Mr. Li will agree or not.
李主任会不会答应
Don't be nervous.
别紧张
Let's do our best.
咱们尽力而为吧
Dango,
团子
that day I went shopping...
我那天去买东西
Hello?
喂
Is this Mu Xiaoyu?
是牧小鱼吗
Your package has arrived.
你的快递到了
I'm downstairs now.
我现在在楼下
It's glass,
这是玻璃制品
you'll need to come down and sign for it.
得自己下来签收
Coming.
来了
Hey!
哎 哎 哎
Dango, this is bad!
团子 团子 不好了
The situation has changed.
情况有变
Your Prince Charming's
你男神
second period class
原本第二节专业课
moved to first period.
改到第一节了
He's about to leave the dormitory now
他现在就要出寝室
and go to Building One!
去一号楼了
- OK. - There's not much time.
好好好 赶紧的 好
You and Xiaoyu should come quickly.
你跟小鱼赶紧过来啊
No!
不是
I...
我
Where is Dango?
团子呢
The confession has been moved forward.
表白提前了
What?
什么
Do you want to go and have a look?
你想不想一起去看看
I'm not going.
我不去
I didn't tell her just now.
我刚才就没告诉她
I can't go to the execution ground
我现在还去刑场
and see her get rejected.
上看她被拒啊
I'm not going.
我不去
Hey.
哎
Have you considered
你有没有想过
there might be a worse possibility?
更坏的一种情况
What?
什么呀
What if
万一
the guy agrees?
这个男的同意了
If he is such a scum,
这男的要敢这么渣
I'll never forgive him!
我饶不了他
Hey!
哎 哎
Together!
在一起 在一起
You're shouting too early.
你喊早了 喊早了
Senpai, I...
学长 我
Sorry, I have a class to go to.
抱歉 我还有课
I'm off.
先走了
It's okay, Dango.
行了 团子
Stop crying.
咱不哭了啊
When we leave this hot pot restaurant
出了这火锅店
you'll definitely find a more handsome,
肯定能找一更帅
and better guy.
更好的
Dango.
团子
Why didn't you tell me earlier
你怎么不早告诉我
it was Liu Yanze?
说是刘彦泽啊
If you'd told me it was him,
你要早告诉我说是他
I wouldn't have let you go.
我根本就不会让你去
You two know each other?
你俩认识啊
I more than know him.
何止是认识
We're enemies.
那简直就是仇人
You're enemies? What happened?
你俩什么仇 什么怨啊
It's a long story.
三言两语说不清楚
Basically we two are irreconcilable.
总之不共戴天
Being mysterious, huh?
神神秘秘的
Xiaoyu.
小鱼
I should have listened to you before.
我之前就应该听你的
I shouldn't be so impulsive.
我不应该那么冲动
I knew it!
我就知道
From now on,
从今往后
I'm going to wait for a
我团子要等那些
Prince Charming to chase me.
男神过来追我
That's the spirit!
有志气
Cheers to that!
咱走一个
Cheers!
干杯
Hao sent a message.
小好姐来微信了
She's asking where we are.
问咱们在哪儿呢
Let's take a picture for her.
咱给她拍个照片吧
Say we'll go back straight after we finish eating.
说吃完这顿饭马上回去
My makeup is all smudged. Let me fix it.
我妆都花了 我修一下
The photos are still there.
里面还有照片呢
The date of this photo was taken
这照片日期是
a few days ago.
几天前拍的
You already knew!
你早就知道了
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我呀
Yeah, why didn't you tell her?
对 你怎么不告诉她呀
I'm also responsible.
我也有责任
Dango.
团子
Actually, we wanted to tell you.
其实我们是想告诉你的
Then why didn't you?
那你为什么不说呀
We had our reasons.
我们有原因
What reasons?
你什么原因啊
You kept such a big thing from me!
你这么大的事你瞒着我
It's about that, Dango,
主要是 团子
we didn't have any proof.
这事 咱也没有证据
Right?
对不对
They checked into a room, isn't that proof?
都开房了还没有证据
What if they were practicing scripts together?
他们万一研究剧本呢
What are you talking about?
你说什么
He said that.
他 他说的
Me?
我
It was me.
是我 是我
Dango, I know you are angry.
团子 我知道你生气
I also feel bad.
我也特别难受
Ever since I knew about this,
我自打知道这事以后
I haven't felt at ease for a moment.
我一刻都没有安生过
Not for one moment.
我真一刻都没有安生过
But I convinced myself,
但我就说服我自己
what if this guy likes you, too?
万一这男的也喜欢你呢
What if this guy says yes?
万一这男的答应你了呢
Then I'll be his mistress!
那我不就成了小三了
Yeah.
是啊
She'll be his mistress!
她万一她就成小三了
I can testify,
我 我做证啊
she really didn't think of that,
她真没想到这一层
really.
真的
She didn't think about that?
没有想到这一层
Then did you two ever think,
那你们有没有想过
you two are my best friends,
你们是我最好的朋友呀
you knew the truth,
你们明明知道真相
and didn't tell me.
却不告诉我
Do you know how sad I am now?
那我现在有多难过
Dango, drink some Coke.
团子 喝口可乐
Shut up!
给我闭嘴
Ouch!
哎哟喂
Mu Xiaoyu.
牧小鱼
I don't care that I got rejected,
我表白失败不算什么
it's not the first time, is it?
也不是第一次了吧
You,
你
and Nanbei,
还有南北
you two keeping secrets from me,
你们两个人瞒着我
is what disappointed me!
让我失望透顶
Don't yell at him.
你别吼他
It has nothing to do with him.
这事跟他没有关系
It was all my idea.
都是我的主意
You said it too just now
刚才你也说了
we are best friends.
咱们是最好的朋友
I was really afraid
我是真的怕你
that after you found out this
知道这事之后
you'd be really sad.
特别难过
Am I not sad now anyway?
那我现在就不难过了
Ah!
啊
There's no trust
我们竟然连
among us at all!
一点信任都没有
We shouldn't be friends at all!
我们都不配做朋友
Dango!
团子 团子
Calm down.
你冷静点
Put yourself in our shoes
你站在我们的角度
and think about it.
想一想
Really,
真的
it's not an easy thing
这事真不是
to tell.
那么好说出口的
Really, there is too much taboo.
真的 这忌讳太多了
Like when I lost Xiaoyu's
你像我把小鱼的小小鱼
Little Xiaoyu,
给弄丢了
I was afraid to say anything.
我也不敢说
I was really scared.
我真不敢呀
It was too hard.
太难了
What are you talking about?
你说什么
No!
不是
They're doing life-drawing at the comic book club tomorrow.
明天漫画社有写生
You two tell Hao
你们俩跟小好姐说一声
I'm not going to the competition.
比赛我就不去了
No!
不是
If you don't we'll be short-handed.
你不去我们人手不够了
Get a substitute.
让编外替补上
Dango.
团子
Where's my son?
我儿子呢
He...
它
...ran away from home.
离家出走了
No.
不行
Mr. Li,
李主任
We understand that when two schools merge,
我们理解两校合并
you need to choose a new school team.
要选一个新校队出来
But we're both school teams,
可是都是校队
isn't it too arbitrary
就这么选了西科大
to just pick the Western University of Science and Technology team?
是不是太武断了点
Let me tell you something.
我跟你讲啊
About that,
这件事情
you're not the only ones fighting for it.
不是你们一个人在争取
As soon as the merger was announced,
合并消息一出
Captain Liu Yanze
西科大辩论队
from the Western University of Science and Technology's team
队长刘彦泽
has been fighting for it.
一直在争取
They've recently participated
他们最近又参加了几次
in several high-level competitions.
高水平的比赛
You've seen too.
你们也看到了吧
They won them all.
全都赢了
But...
可是
I hope you can understand.
我希望你们能理解我啊
This is
这件事情
not something I can decide
真不是我一个人
on my own.
能说了算的
I have work to do.
我还有事要忙
Why don't you head back?
你们先回去吧
Mr. Li...
主任
Go back.
回去 回去吧
- Go back. - Mr. Li!
回去 主任
Maybe you were right.
还是你说得对
I should have told Dango.
我就应该告诉团子
I wish I had listened to you.
早知道听你的就好了
Dango is still angry.
团子还在气头上呢
When her anger subsides and she calms down,
等她气消了冷静下来
I'm sure she can understand.
肯定就能明白了
Then we'll wait for her to come back,
那等她回来
and apologize to her.
肯定跟她好好道歉
Where's Dango?
团子呢
There's something I need to tell you.
有件事我要跟你们说
Something happened with Dango.
团子她有点事
She might not be able
明天比赛
to come to tomorrow's competition.
她可能来不了了
Hm.
嗯
See?
看见了
This is what happened.
她这个事
It seems like
看样子
you three
你们三个
haven't prepared for the competition.
也没有准备比赛吧
Hao, don't be angry.
小好姐 你别生气
We'll go prepare now.
我们这就去准备
It's not too late.
肯定也来得及
Let's go.
走 走
There's no need.
不用准备了
After the school merger,
两校合并
it was decided
校方决定
that the Western University of Science and Technology
由原西科大的校队
will serve as the school team.
担任校队
Our team
我们队
has been disbanded.
解散了
Why? How?
为什么 凭什么
Calm down.
冷静 冷静 冷静
Sit.
坐坐坐
No,
不是
why are they disbanding our team?
为什么要解散我们队啊
Right!
就是啊
Why can't
他们队
their team be disbanded?
凭什么不能解散啊
Mr. Li showed me
李主任给我看了
their competition results from last year.
他们去年的成绩
They were a lot better than us.
确实比我们强很多
Ours weren't bad!
咱们队的成绩也不差
We had ups and downs,
是不太稳定
but there were times when we did really well.
但也有发挥好的时候啊
Why don't we compete with them and see who's best?
把他们拉出来比试比试
We won't necessarily win.
比也不一定赢
Their captain Liu Yanze
他们那个队长刘彦泽
is said to have won so many best debater titles.
据说是最佳辩手专业户
Liu Yanze...
刘彦泽
Here comes a chance for revenge.
报仇的机会来了
We'll settle our old scores and new.
新仇旧账老子一起算
What do you mean?
什么意思
He's the guy in the video
他就是视频里面
who bullied Dango.
欺负我们团子那个坏蛋
This is all because of him.
所有的事情都是因为他
Let's go over there and settle this.
上门算账去
Let's go!
走
Come back.
回来 回来 回来
Calm down, sit.
冷静 坐坐坐
Sit down.
坐
What are you doing?
干嘛呀
Thrashing around and making a scene.
撒泼打滚啊
If that works,
撒泼打滚要是有用的话
we'd have
那今天
done that today.
我们俩就用上了
This is also difficult for me to accept.
我也很不甘心
But Mr. Li has made it clear
但是李主任已经明确地
and said no to us.
拒绝我们了
There really is no way.
确实没有办法了
Do you remember how I used to
还记不记得我平时
teach you all?
怎么教你们的
For anything,
任何事情
the most effective solution is
最有效的解决办法就是
to find the pain point.
找痛点
You've done
这边的工作
good work here.
你做得不错呀
Right,
对呀
what you said
我其实我想的
was exactly what I was thinking.
您说的是非常正确
Yes.
是
Well...
这个
What have you planned
那你下一段工作
for your future work?
怎么打算
What's going on here?
这什么情况
Come.
来
First team, go.
第一队出动
Alpha, go.
阿尔法出动
Everybody, go.
所有人 出动
Go!
走
Hello, Vice-Chancellor.
副校长 您好
I'm Nanbei from the debate team.
我是校辩论队的南北
Welcome to our university.
欢迎您来考察学校
What's going on here?
这什么情况
Is this a surprise
这是李主任
your organized for me, Mr. Li?
你给我的惊喜吗
This...
这个
Vice-Chancellor,
副校长
this is a welcoming ceremony
这是我们校辩论队
volunteered and organized
自告奋勇
by our school debate team.
组织的欢迎仪式
Oh!
哟
There's a card, too!
还有卡片啊
Let me see.
我看看 我看看啊
I love you.
我爱你
Huh?
啊
Be with me.
和我在一起
Let me look.
不是 我看一下
No.
没有 没有
Well, Vice-Chancellor...
那个 副校长
I... I love you means
我 我爱你是
all the members of our school debate team
我们校辩论队全体成员
are all very grateful for your
对您长期以来的
long-standing support.
栽培的感谢
It also means that
也 也代表了我们
we hope we can
希望和您
be with you forever.
永远在一起的心情
How heartfelt.
用心了 用心了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
So,
这么说
you're
这位学生
a member of the debate team?
你是辩论队的
Yes.
啊是
I'm very proud
我 我很骄傲
to be a member of the debate team.
我是辩论队的一员
It's just that...
只不过
Just what?
只不过什么
Mr. Li said
李主任说
our debate team
我们的辩论队
will be disbanded soon.
马上就要解散了
Li,
我说 老李
you can't beat down
这么有干劲的学生
the motivation
可不能打击
of such passionate students.
他们积极性啊
Right.
对呀 对对对
But Vice-Chancellor-
但是校长你不知道
Mr. Li.
李 李主任
We still have another
一会儿我们
competition in a bit.
还有一场比赛
If we win
如果我们赢了
the competition,
拿到了比赛
could you reconsider?
你能不能再考虑考虑
Keep your distance!
来来来 给我保持距离
Vice-Chancellor,
那个副校长
we also hope that
我们也希望
you and Mr. Li
你和李主任
can come watch our competition.
一会儿一起来观看
A competition?
比赛
Right?
是吧
OK.
好啊
This reminds me of my
这让我想起了澎湃
exciting college life.
的大学生活了
Hm.
嗯
I think we can.
我看可以
But, Chancellor,
但是 校长
there's a lot
我办公室
of work to do at my office.
有很多工作要做
- I need to get back. - Mr. Li.
我就必须得回 李主任
Your office work
办公室的工作
can be done without you.
不需要您也能完成
What do you say?
说你呢
Alright.
行
Chancellor,
校长
how about this?
我看这样好不好
This afternoon
下午呢
we'll go and watch the debate.
我们俩一块去看比赛
Suppose that they win
假如说他们赢了
as a result,
有了结果
we'll reopen our discussion
辩论队的事情
on the debate team issue.
我们重新再讨论一下
What do you think?
您觉得怎么样
Sure.
可以啊
You know, students.
学生嘛
Their activities
他们的活动
are all about results.
还是要成绩说话的
Right?
对吧
Do your best!
好好打
Win,
打赢了
and we can reconsider.
咱们可以重新研究嘛
Great!
好
Thank you, sir.
谢谢老师
Together!
在一起 在一起
You don't need to shout that.
这个不用喊
Reconsider.
重新研究
What does that word mean?
这四个字意味着什么
It means hope.
意味着希望
It means a lighthouse in the ocean.
意味着汪洋中的灯塔
The rays of dawn in the dark.
黑暗中的曙光
Gorky once said...
高尔基曾经说过
Mr. Sa,
小撒老师
we don't even have enough people.
我们人都不够
Do you think that while
你以为当你们这些
you lovely students
可爱的学生
were shooting your shot,
在放手一搏的时候
as your teacher
作为老师
I'd do nothing?
会无所作为吗
Let me introduce,
下面就让我来介绍
an outstanding student from Dongcai University's Chinese department,
东财大中文系高才生
winner of the national scholarship
连续三年国家奖学金
for three consecutive years,
获得者
Gong.
小宫
H... ello, every... one.
大家好
I'm Gong.
我是小宫
Come here.
过来 过来 过来
What's going on?
什么情况这是
He's the only one who signed up.
就他一个人报名
Make do with him.
凑合着用吧
How can we make do with him?
这 这怎么凑合
How?
怎么凑合
Do your best.
尽量凑合
We don't have much time.
时间紧迫
Just a few hours.
我们只有几个小时了
The opponent is Donggang University of Political Science.
对面是东港政法
They're also a strong team.
也是一支强队
We should take them seriously.
大家不能掉以轻心
Come on, let's start with rebuttals.
来吧 先拆论吧
But I don't think there's enough time.
但我觉得时间有点不够
Isn't it better to use common sense
要不还是按照常识
and do the structure first?
认知先做框架
Guys, to be on the safe side
同志们 稳妥起见
I think we should start
我觉得我们应该先
with data research.
做数据搜索
There's definitely no time for that.
那时间肯定不够
If there is not enough time,
时间不够的话
we should do rebuttals first,
我们就应该先拆论
build our speeches and rebuttals at the same time.
边拆论边出论呢
But usually...
可是按照往常
Usually we do rebuttals first.
往常我们就是先拆论
For us...
对于我们来讲
It's important to be on the safe side...
稳妥才是重要
Data research...
数据搜索
Alright.
好了 好了
Listen to me.
这时候就听我的吧
You...
你来
We don't have much time. Don't make trouble.
时间紧 别闹
Let's just do
我们还是做
what we're best at.
自己最擅长的
Me and Xiaoyu will do the rebuttals.
我和小鱼拆论
Hao,
小好姐
make a structure based on
你根据常识认知
some common knowledge information.
基础上做框架
Sa,
小撒
we're leave the rebuttal points
我们把拆论点
for you to organize.
交给你整理
Gong.
小宫
Help Sa.
你帮助小撒
Find data and info to support the argument.
根据论点查数据和资料
Alright?
可以吧
No problems?
都没问题吧
Let's get started.
开始吧
Can't you be normal?
正常点行不行
Making so much noise all the time.
吵死了一天天的
Weren't the debate team
东财大原校辩论队
from Dongcai University disbanded?
不是都解散了吗
Why has the competition this afternoon been rescheduled?
下午比赛怎么又上了
They thought if they won the competition
他们以为赢下比赛
they could compete with us
就能和我们争夺
to become the school debate team.
校队名额吧
They're dreaming.
异想天开
Gong.
小宫
You are crucial
你的发挥
to the outcome
对这场比赛的胜负
of this competition.
至关重要
I'm sure you all know.
我相信你们都知道
Today,
今天
it's a battle for our survival.
是咱们生死存亡的一战
Go for it.
加油
Let's go.
出发
There's no time to get emotional.
没时间煽情了
I already knew about
西科大的阴谋
the Western University of Science and Technology's plot.
我已经知道了
How is the preparation of
你们的论点
argument points going?
准备得怎么样
Let me have a look.
让我看一下
And get me something to wear for the competition.
再给我一件上场的衣服
Even though my storyline was cut,
虽然我的剧情被砍了
I still find this really exciting!
但是我觉得好燃哪
After hearing excellent points and questions
听了双方辩手的
from both sides,
精彩立论和质询
next let's hear from
接下来让我们一起欣赏
the third speakers on each side.
双方三辩的
Debate one-to-one.
一对一攻辩环节
Third speakers, please begin.
有请双方三辩
Hello, opponent.
对方辩友你好
May I ask my opponent,
请问对方辩友
concealing something out of kindness,
善意的隐瞒
is kind to everyone?
对所有人都是善意的吗
Yes.
是的
Kind to you and kind to him.
对己对他都善意
Everyone benefits.
都有利
So why not do it?
何乐而不为呢
I'll give an example,
举个例子
if a companion of my friend
朋友的伴侣
went into a hotel with a stranger.
和陌生人出入酒店
I would rather tear down ten temples
我本着宁拆十座庙
than destroy a relationship.
不毁一桩婚的善意
And I concealed this.
隐瞒了这件事情
But in the end, there was no concealing the truth.
最终纸包不住火
She lost her love.
她丢了爱情
I lost a friend.
我失去了朋友
But who benefits from
这份善意
that kindness?
到底对谁有利呢
No one.
对谁都不利
Isn't that exactly
这不正好是
what happens when you fail to conceal something?
隐瞒失败的后果吗
I'm afraid my opponent is demonstrating
对方辩友怕不是论证了
our side's point of view.
我方观点吧
He turned it around on them.
偷换主体了
And if I had succeeded in concealing it
隐瞒成功的结果
then that friend
就是您的朋友
would have been cheated on
被戴了绿帽子
and you'd be unaffected.
而您则明哲保身
This is totally different
这和您说的
from the "good for everybody" theory
你好 我好 大家好
you were talking about.
可不是一回事啊
My opponent,
对方辩友
this is a misinterpretation of our side's
这是在曲解我方
criteria for judging kindness.
对于善意的判别标准
I didn't ask about the criteria.
我没有问判断标准
I asked about the definition.
我问的是定义
Since you can't prove
既然您没办法证明
your own definition,
自己的定义的话
then,
那请问
what are the criteria for judging kindness?
善意的判断标准是什么
Our side believes that
我方认为
judging whether
判断隐瞒
something is concealed out of kindness or not
是否善意的标准
is about who bears the consequences.
就是谁来承担这个后果
If I bear
只有我承担
the consequences of what I concealed,
自己隐瞒的后果
that's kindness.
那才是善意的
If you bear the consequences yourself, then it's kindness.
自己承担的就是善意的
So these consequences
所以这个后果
are bad, right?
就是不好的对吗
You can interpret it like that.
你要这么理解也可以
Then why would an act of kindness
那为什么一个善意之举
bring with it
却会带来了一个
bad consequences?
不好的后果呢
Who says acts of kindness
谁说善举
will definitely have good consequences?
一定会带来善果呢
If you know there will be bad consequences,
至少明知道会有恶果
it can't be called an act of kindness.
就肯定称不上是善举
Not concealing it would bring
不隐瞒会带来
greater harm.
更大的伤害
And if you hide it
而如果隐瞒
you can minimize the damage.
可以把伤害降到最低
This is the best solution.
这是一个最优解
Does the opposition not understand?
您方是听不懂吗
So the precondition of concealing something
所以善意的隐瞒
out of kindness is
要以对自己的不善
is being unkind to yourself?
为前提
Your argument
您的论点
contradicts itself again.
再一次自相矛盾
For the third time.
第三次了 对方辩友
My opponent,
对方辩友
I wish you wouldn't hold on all the time to...
我希望你不要总抓着
They cut off a large part of the battlefield.
切掉了一大块战场
It'll be easier from now on.
后面好打了
Free debate,
自由辩攻击
attack on points one, three and four.
对方一三四点
Next is what you've all been looking forward to,
下面就是大家最期待的
the intense and exciting free debate.
紧张刺激的自由辩论了
In the free debate
自由辩论
each side has four minutes.
每方计时四分钟
We'll begin with the opposing side.
由反方先开始
Go ahead.
有请
If one of your friends at work
假如您同公司的朋友
made a mistake,
犯了错误
and the company talked to you for his background check
公司找您去做背景调查
would you conceal it for your friend?
请问您会替朋友隐瞒吗
If my friend had really changed
如果朋友真心改正
then I would conceal it
那我会隐瞒
and give him a chance.
给他一个机会
This is what we mean by the best solution.
这就是我方说的最优解
But this concealment is out of
可是这样的隐瞒对
kindness to your friend,
朋友是善意的
but has ill intent towards the new company.
对新公司就有点恶意了
May I ask, is an ill-intent concealment
请问恶意的隐瞒
also necessary?
也是有必要的吗
Concealment out of kindness is necessary.
善意的隐瞒有必要性
That doesn't mean
不是说任何时候
it's necessary at
都是必要的
any given time.
都必然要隐瞒啊
So your view is,
所以您方的观点是
concealment out of kindness
善意的隐瞒
is sometimes necessary
有时候是必要的
and sometimes unnecessary.
有时候是不必要的
With all due respect,
恕我直言
isn't that nonsense?
这不是句废话吗
This point has been won.
这个点拿下了
Let's look at necessity.
来 我们来看必要性
When you're in love
当谈恋爱的时候
and out of kindness,
善意地隐瞒
conceal some of your past,
一点点恋爱史
won't it reduce conflicts with your partner?
是不是减少伴侣矛盾的
Is that necessary?
必要手段呢
That's not reducing conflict,
那不是减少矛盾
that's a hidden bomb.
那是埋下隐患
According to your logic,
按照您方的逻辑
when you get married
那结婚的时候
is it necessary
是不是有必要
to conceal your family and
隐瞒家庭情况
financial situation?
和经济状况呢
My opponent's example
您方的举例
is of concealment with ill intent.
属于恶意隐瞒
When I'm in love,
在恋爱中
and my partner
如果我对象
asks for details about me
问起我跟前女友
and my ex-girlfriend,
之间的细节
I conceal them.
我隐瞒了
Isn't that better
是不是比
than just directly talking about it?
直接说出来好啊
Your partner doesn't need
您对象本身就没有必要
to know about it.
知道这件事情
Then this is not called concealment.
那这个就不叫隐瞒
If we call this concealment too,
如果这个都叫隐瞒的话
then does a teacher conceal
那是不是在考试之前
the test questions before an exam?
老师也隐瞒了试题呢
When something is concealed out of kindness,
请问在善意的隐瞒中
doesn't the person who is being lied to have the right to know?
被隐瞒者是否有知情权
Not necessarily.
不一定嘛
For example, when we're studying away from home,
比如说在外求学的我们
if we encounter problems,
如果磕了碰了
don't we often not want to
是不是也往往不想
make our parents worry,
让父母担心
and conceal it out of kindness?
而选择善意的隐瞒呢
All primary school kids know
小学生都知道
the story of the wolf.
狼来了的故事
If it goes on like that,
长此以往
parents can no longer believe you
父母不再相信
when you tell them you're as safe and sound.
你报的平安
and get even more worried.
反而更加担心了
What can they do?
怎么办呢
So you can also
所以你也可以
choose to tell the truth.
选择说实话呀
So you admit that
所以您方也承认
I can choose not to hide it?
我可以选择不隐瞒
Wouldn't that be consenting
那岂不是承认
that concealment isn't necessary?
隐瞒是不必要的了
My opponent,
对方辩友不要
you shouldn't play word games.
玩文字游戏
Let's talk about
我们来谈一个
a serious topic.
严肃的话题
In the face
面对一个身患
of a terminally ill patient,
绝症的病人
a better state of mind
更好的心态
is obviously more conducive
显然更加有利于
to his treatment.
他的治疗
So at this time,
这个时候
isn't the doctor's concealment
医生善意的隐瞒
necessary?
是否有必要
Of course not.
当然不可以
From September 1st, 2012,
2012年9月1日起
Regulations on the
施行的医疗
Treatment of Medical Malpractice,
事故处理条例
Article 11 expressly stipulates that
第十一条明文规定
doctors should check the patient's condition
医生应当将患者的病情
and truthfully
如实告知
and timely tell them the answer.
及时解答
My opponent has concealed the second part of that article.
对方辩友隐瞒了后半条
There's another sentence that says
这后面还有一句叫但是
adverse consequences to
应避免对患者
the patient should be avoided.
产生不利的后果
Is concealment necessary
请问在比赛中
during a competition?
隐瞒是必要的吗
It's not.
不是必要的
You see,
您看
that concealment by our fourth speaker
刚刚我方四辩的隐瞒
made us pay
让我们付出了
the price of mistake.
错误的代价
And you got applause.
而您方获得了掌声
Doesn't this mean that,
这不正说明了
concealment is not only unnecessary,
隐瞒非但不是必要的
it's also inadvisable?
更是不可取的吗
The opposition is out of time.
反方时间用尽
The proposition still has 17 seconds.
正方剩余十七秒
There's so much time left
可时间上剩余这么多
for the other side to attack.
对方轮番攻击
We'll be in a very passive position.
场面就会很被动
What are they going to do?
怎么办呢
However, my opponent,
可是对方辩友
very often the truth
很多时候真相
brings harm with it.
往往会带来伤害
Is this kind of concealment
这种隐瞒
really unnecessary?
难道是不必要的吗
Your side has always
您方一直在质疑
been questioning our criteria for necessity.
我方的必要性标准
What are yours?
您方的标准何在呢
Is paying a price
付出代价就一定
always inadvisable?
是不可取的吗
My opponent seems to think
对方辩友似乎认为
that the truth is glorious,
真相是伟光正的
and ignoring all of the confusion,
对生活中所有的迷茫
embarrassment
尴尬
and entanglement
和纠结
in life.
统统无视
But this is not the case.
然而并不是这样
Truth is a neutral word.
真相是一个中立词
It can also bring harm.
它也会带来伤害
Can't it?
不是吗
Time's up.
时间到
The opposition's second speaker has the right
反方二辩发动
to launch a surprise attack.
奇袭的权利
Do you choose to make an inquiry
请问您是选择质询
or a statement?
还是申论
A statement.
申论
My opponent said
对方辩友说
that truth can bring harm
真相会带来伤害
so concealment is necessary.
所以隐瞒是必要的
My opponent,
对方辩友
truth does no harm.
真相不会带来伤害
When truth is ignored,
真相被忽略
it will bring harm.
才会带来伤害
It will hurt
它会伤害我们
the thing we hold most dear,
最珍贵的东西
trust.
信任
Just a few days ago,
就在几天前
I hid something
我怀揣着
from my best friend
自以为是的善意
out of self-righteous kindness.
隐瞒了我最好的朋友
And that moment when
然后当得知
she learned the truth,
真相的那一刻
the way she looked at me
这份自以为是
smashed that self-righteousness
被她看向我的眼神
to pieces.
击得粉碎
Because in her eyes
因为那眼神里
there was only disappointment.
只有失望
Was it because my intentions
是因为我的善意
weren't kind enough?
不够多吗
Or that my concealment
还是我的隐瞒
led to bad consequences?
造成了多恶劣的后果呢
It was neither.
都不是
What really made her angry
真正让她生气的
was precisely that concealment itself.
恰恰是隐瞒本身
Even if you say
哪怕它的背后有一句
it's for their own good,
为你好
even if it's given
哪怕它被冠以
the name of kindness.
善意的称号
There are many things in this world,
这个世界上很多东西
caring for friends,
对朋友的在意
concern for loved ones,
对亲人的牵挂
those can all be described
他们会被扣上一个
as kindness.
善意的定语
It seems that as long as you add "kindness,"
似乎只要加在前面
bad things will become better,
坏的就会变好
concealment will become a necessity,
隐瞒就变成了必要
and going beyond the line will become natural.
过分就成为了理所当然
But is that kindness?
可这是善意吗
That's arrogance.
这是傲慢
Anything I do for "your own good,"
所有的为你好
is announcing loudly
都是在大声宣告
that I'll make a decision for you.
我来替你做出决定
But which one of us has
可是我们谁又拥有
the right to make
替别人做出
decisions for others?
决定的权利呢
Why should we force our
我们又凭什么将自己
judgments of good or bad
对好坏的判断
onto others
强加于别人身上
and ask them to
还要让人家去
be grateful for it?
领你这一份情呢
Please be honest with each other,
请坦诚相待
because nobody
因为没有人
wants to live
愿意生活在
in the cage of ignorance.
无知的笼子里
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm telling you,
我就跟你说
separating us
想拆了我们
isn't that easy!
没有那么容易
Right!
就是
We three sisters,
我们三姐妹
three swords united!
三剑合璧
No one can beat us!
谁也打不赢我们
So we're good now, right?
那我们算和好了吧
When were we bad?
我们什么时候不好了
Guys.
同学们
I haven't prepared anything,
我 我没有准备
but at this moment,
但是此时此刻
I would like to say a few words.
我想说两句
Gorky once said...
高尔基曾经说过
Mr. Li is calling.
李主任来电话了
Mr. Li.
李主任
Hello, Hao.
喂 小好啊
Ask all members
明天早上让
of the debate team to come to my office
辩论队的所有队员
for a meeting tomorrow.
来我办公室开个会
The school team issue
校队的事情
has been decided.
已经定下来了
And?
结果是
A merger.
合并
Even though
你们呢
you narrowly won the debate,
虽然是险胜了比赛
their team
但是他们在新校区啊
beat last year's
赢了去年的
national champion, South Jiaotong University.
全国总冠军南交大
You could say
合并呢
merging is the best outcome
可以说是我争取到
I could have achieved.
最好的结果了
How about this?
这样吧
I'll send you
我把他们的资料
their information.
给你发过去
Have a look.
你看一下
What's the matter?
怎么了
Yin Nan.
殷楠
Who is Yin Nan?
谁是殷楠
Xiaoyu's enemy.
小鱼仇人